hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
microkowski and in this podcast I help
coaches mentors speakers trainers people
that have a message
that want to reach others with their
message and make a whole heck of a lot
of money do so with the strategies tips
resources and mindset to break past
what's stopping them and today I'm going
to talk to you about something that has
been on my heart for a while something I
haven't really talked about very much
but something I think that is so
important and what it is is if you are
somebody who is working a corporate job
or you work a job you work for somebody
else how do you also build a business
and how do you balance that time and how
do you make the time to be able to
accomplish everything now I'm not gonna
pretend like I have all the answers to
this but I did build my business while I
was working in corporate Consulting
situations and I have a lot of my
clients as well that work a corporate
job but also want to build a business
one of the the two number one things
that people tell me that they struggle
with is they don't have the financial
resource sources but they also don't
have the time to accomplish things and
so what I want to do is give you a few
strategies that you can use to be able
to unlock more time in your life more
time to build your business and to start
to do things and to start to move the
needle forward here's one of the first
things that I want to recommend is break
things down into smaller chunks okay
and and this might sound like uh well
duh everybody says that but that's like
practically how to actually do that let
me explain
we break down in our business for
coaches mentors trainers and speakers
it's called the six steps step number
one is finding your Niche or topic that
you're going to coach on and for most
people that's where they're stuck that's
where they're struggling there are now
resources out there that you can use to
help you get unstuck such as chat GPT
chat GPT is an artificial intelligence
engine that you can talk to and share
you know how you want to accomplish
things what are some different ways to
accomplish things you can get advice you
can get resources Direction and it's a
powerful tool that you can use also to
help you with uncovering what are some
great topics that you could coach on
what are some great ideas that you could
use for instance I want to coach women
to be more financially independent
I didn't even spell that right but
that's okay it doesn't actually have to
be spelled right I'm going to show you
the how how quickly and easily this is
you don't have to spell it right the AI
knows what I meant okay
um generate 20 possible niches
that are most profitable to help these
women
20 possible niches to help them with
financial Independence so
entrepreneurship coaching financial
literacy Investing For Women
um career advancement see so right away
those are women in Tech
um divorce financial planning single
moms financial planning retirement
planning financial planning for
entrepreneurs wealth management money
mindset coaching Financial Independence
retire early
and so let's take a look at these right
here these are all very different these
are all very different niches but if you
found one specifically
you could dive into it and really start
to create an incredible offer for some
people let's take this one
let's take this idea and unpack
20 sub niches
and possibly Industries or categories
that would be most profitable
for me as a coach because you want to be
profitable as a coach
2017 so specifically women in corporate
leadership
salary negotiation coaching while women
in Tech Career transition coaching
usually the top four or five are what
I'm finding are probably going to be the
most profitable for people uh returning
to work is also really good right here
actually this is really good right here
let's take this one let's unpack 20
possible sub niches based on this
I don't need to explain it multiple
times it already knows what I meant
returning to Tech return ship programs
skills upgrade programs confidence
building so right here this could be
your coaching program right there so you
can utilize tools like chat GPT to come
up with ideas for your coaching business
and break things down very simply very
easily you could host a live Zoom event
on a Saturday
Market that out to people take 300 in
Facebook ads use what we teach with
Facebook ads to be able to create
a uh an offer and so for instance again
chat GPT helps you create your sales
copy helps you create your offers I'm
not going to go into that in this
training we have a number of other
trainings on my YouTube where I walk you
through how to do this
um so be sure to check those out how to
use chat jbt to write your sales copy
and do your marketing on my YouTube
channel what I want to talk about though
is if you're in a job how are you
actually going to find the time to be
able to create all of this
well what you want to do is you want to
shift a your mindset the first thing to
shift is going to be out of this mindset
that I am a victim because I'm at a job
okay and this might be one of the
hardest things that you do but realize
I'm not that you're not a victim to your
circumstance to your health to your
energy to the amount of time you have or
the amount of financial resources that
you have okay so that's going to be a
big shift
that shift alone out of victim mindset
is gonna unlock for you creativity
because when we operate out of the
victim mindset which is also a lack
mindset of I don't have enough I don't
have enough time I don't have enough
energy I don't have enough resources
that's not negating that by the way I I
fully understand that that might like
that is your reality okay if that is
your reality
but we have to not be a victim to our
reality Okay so
put that on a shelf and say okay this is
going on this is happening in my life
but it's not going to Define what I'm
capable of okay
and that again when we when we answer
that we want to address
you know why do we let it Define us what
are we trying to avoid happening what
are we afraid might happen if we don't
let that thing Define us
what what are we trying to make sure
doesn't happen again
by operating out of this cycle and that
is a question that you can ask yourself
that it might point to a past experience
whether it be in your childhood whether
it be at your job itself you literally
might have abuse going on in your
workplace that has wired your brain and
gaslighted you
in the thinking that you can't get out
of this situation or that you can't
adjust it you can't maneuver it
and that's very difficult because it's
essentially a high level form of
brainwashing corporate I believe the
corporate environment is a high level of
brainwashing where people are
brainwashed to serve the vision of the
company corporations are essentially uh
micro Cults that people give their time
to in exchange for a paycheck and they
have an altruistic reason why they want
to stay on board with these often you're
passionate about what you're doing I
totally get it I absolutely get it I
absolutely understand it this is one of
the biggest reasons why I struggle to
quit jobs why I struggle to cancel
contracts that were sucking the life out
of me is because of how I was thinking
and what what I was getting out of the
corporate environment okay so the first
thing to look at is a you're not a
victim to actually take ownership of the
fact that you are choosing to stay in
that job
that you are choosing to continue to
actually do what you're doing
that you have actually chosen to invest
your time over here
and what this does is this puts you into
a power position in how you're actually
thinking so you want to be in a power
position to where no longer are you just
a victim of things coming at you you're
the one deciding what happens next and
and go with me here on a journey of
if you had the power to to move some
pieces around at your job or to change
how you do things to change your hours
to change how your job operates I tell
you this
an unlock for some people that I've
actually recognized
for their business is for them not to
just quit their job but to get another
job that is more flexible
to get a second job that pays a little
bit more but has more flex and then what
this does is this provides to be able to
actually build the business this
actually gives the extra time the extra
energy and the extra Financial Resources
to build the business
so you're not just going cold turkey
you're just moving and transitioning and
pivoting the direction I did that as
well in my own uh experience
as when I stopped working with my mom
full time I got a bunch of client work
that I was doing and now that client
work consumed all of my time we were
making six figures so I had to figure
out okay how can I shrink the client
work
so that it's taking less of my time and
actually Shrunk the client work down to
10 hours a week and we were still making
six figures this was incredible because
then it unlocked for me the extra time
that I needed to build my business and
our business started making six figures
and as soon as that happened I went full
into the coaching business and it 4xed
itself
some people ask when's the right time to
quit the job and go full time into the
coaching business it's usually when you
have replaced at least 50 percent of
your income at the job
because then you could go part-time with
the job split your time in half and
double your income in the business very
easily
so half is actually enough to either
quit or go part-time and if you've
replaced the job you definitely I would
recommend to take the leap if you've
replaced that job income to then put in
your two weeks notice and go into
building a business now here's the
difference when you're an entrepreneur
there's some mindset shifts that you
need to make
as an entrepreneur that don't serve well
in a corporate environment what you will
find is
as you start to transition in this way
you don't fit into corporate very well
these four mindset shifts are very
powerful they're very important and they
they will allow you to to go to the next
level in your life and in your business
I have them on my blog post here it's
the it's the four habits of people who
want to leave a corporate job that want
to go after their goals one of the
number one things is you have to be okay
with not having all the answers
you have to be okay with
not having building all of the answers
to every question that people that
people ask you have to be okay with
saying I don't have that answer
you also have to be okay with taking
risks and making mistakes on a regular
basis
when you go out there in your business
you're going to to make mistakes you're
going to take risks and things are not
always going to work out how you wanted
them to
you also have to be okay with not being
liked by everybody you want to be
irresistible to a small group of people
and so what ends up happening is when
you start shifting your mindset away
from I need to be liked by everybody for
survival
foreign
I need to have all the answers for
survival
I need to not make mistakes for survival
and you literally shift out of that you
will now have the mental framework of
what it takes to be successful
in a coaching business in a mentorship
business but you can't operate out of
being worried being a pleaser being
people pleasing and expect to get any
sales in a coaching business because you
will be so worried of the next shoe
dropping things not working out and fear
will run your programming fear will run
your decision-making process and so you
have to actually shift that mindset and
it might not shift until you exit
corporate for me it didn't shift four
years after I exited a corporate
environment I had to work with a
therapist to actually shift this mindset
and I'm even still working through this
and realizing you know what I don't need
to please everybody
I don't need to make everybody happy I
don't need to have all the answers I
don't need to do everything perfect
it's okay to make mistakes
it's not the end of the world
and so when you can actually grow in
that way you grow mentally and you grow
in your actions and you grow in in what
you're doing again answer this question
what am I trying to avoid
by having all the answers well I don't
want to look stupid so who cares what's
going to happen if you look stupid what
a corporate job you'll get fired
in a business you just might have a few
nasty comments from people
but at the end of the day those nasty
comments don't really mean a whole lot a
lot of want nasty comments from people
well you can't control other people
they're gonna come in whether you like
it or not
you could do everything perfect and
still have nasty comments come in from
people
okay and so then this doesn't mean that
we're going to be defrauding people or
doing anything illegal or wrong or or or
selling crappy programs that don't
actually work so that's none of that at
all
but what we're talking about is that
you're not going to do everything
perfect in fact your first offer that
you put out there isn't always going to
produce the results and so what you want
to do is while you're working your job
you want to put a few test offers out
there to gather the data that you need
your test offers probably aren't always
going to work and so that's why I
recommend 300 to 500 in a test budget
knowing that you might lose that and
that is actually part of the cost of
doing business just to get the data and
the feedback of what people that you're
reaching that are out there what they
actually desire
what they actually want what they
actually would like to learn from you
and so by gathering that data then you
are able to build a business
successfully
by providing value to people
that need what you want and when you
start to use their language when you
start talking the language of your
Target customer when you start actually
saying the things that they are saying
the same way that they say it you'll
connect more with people you'll be able
to provide more value
and you'll be able to attract ultimately
people that are ready to buy and spend
money with you
now here's the last thing in your
coaching business you need to start to
talk about bold outcomes and results
that you can create
corporate teaches you to play it safe to
not be bold to Not Over You Know promise
you want to under promise over deliver
I'm sorry but in the coaching business
that's a great way to make zero money
it is it absolutely is
and and most people will argue against
this I am thoroughly convinced more so
than I ever have been
that
this isn't that we are again not
providing value to people but you have
to
in a way over embellish what it is that
you're actually doing what you're
actually selling what you're actually
accomplishing in your sales copy in the
language that you're using in this
industry for it to attract people
because here's the thing your
competitors are doing the same thing and
they're winning and they're making a ton
of money and they're impacting people
and so if you're afraid to do this
because corporate has taught you to play
it safe to you know to to under promise
over deliver to to stay five steps
behind what you can actually accomplish
to not Showboat to not talk too big
about what you can do in case it doesn't
work out these whole Frameworks of
thinking literally are beaten into us by
corporate
and when you can break out of that
mindset it will make you a whole heck of
a lot of money in your coaching business
okay
and so again I want to just encourage
you if you're somebody these are some of
the mindset shifts
you can shift you know
start to create some of the time have a
hard cut have one of the tough
conversations with your boss I did this
years ago or I I was starting to make
six figures in the business and I talked
to my boss and I said hey I want to work
part-time because I'm making this much
over here but I still love what I'm
doing over here
and what was awesome was my boss was
like great let's do it let's go
part-time let's do it and I ended up
leaving that company a few months later
and going freelance and and and then
after that I ended up working with my
mom she became a a client of mine and
then I focused all of my energy into
building an eight-figure business with
my mom and after that we've gone on to
build this business here
you can do it you don't have to be stuck
in just one situation one environment
you're not a prisoner
it might feel like you are
but you're not
and you can break out and you can make
decisions and you can shift your life in
the direction of making a business work
for you
one step at a time and this podcast is a
great resource to help you with that
with the strategies the tips the tools
the resources the mindset shifts that
you need to make a whole heck of a lot
of money in a coaching business all
right make sure to get on our waiting
list for our client growth accelerator
our coaching program where we help you
or we come alongside you and work with
you to build the coaching business that
pays you dividends that you want to make
and make sure to share this podcast with
other people I know that it will help
others just like it's helped you today
grow your life everybody and we'll talk
soon
[Music]